TESS TUCHSCHERER

FOR SOAK BATHHOUSE

ECOMMERCE & DIGITAL MARKETING SPECIALIST

Through my extensive work history, where I've worked primarily in fast-pasted online environments in a number of different departments, I have built a specialised skill set with the advantage of an all-encompassing knowledge of several key areas in the eCommerce domain.

My hands-on approach over studying has provided me the unrivalled experience to grow into a unique position in the field of eCommerce and Marketing, as my career progression allowed me to develop both a logical and creative understanding of data & analytics, visual merchandising, SEO, copywriting, buying and coding. My keen interest in understanding data and skills in coding have been the backbone to my career growth, as I'm able to develop and execute strategies with proven value while remaining true to the integrity of each individual brand.

CONTACT DETAILS

Q 0407 636 864

TESSTUCHSCHERER@GMAIL.COM

NORTHERN RIVERS, NSW

REFERENCES

More available on request.

LAUREL RIGONI **EVENTS LEADER** TOURISM & EVENTS QLD M. 0432 718 410

DANE WALKER CHIEF MARKETING OFFICER PRINCESS POLLY M. 0426 965 152

> DECLAN WISE CEO & CO-FOUNDER AFENDS M. 0401 563 487

EXPERTISE

From systems to skills.

SHOPIFY KLAVIYO META GOOGLE STRATEGIC THINKING DATA & ANALYTICS SEO COPYWRITING MERCHANDISING BUYING HTML & CSS

QUALITIES

If I do say so myself.

CREATIVE & INSPIRED FRIENDLY & CONSCIENTIOUS MATURE & RESPONSIBLE RELIABLE & PUNCTUAL ATTENTIVE & EFFICIENT FAST & ENTHUSIASTIC LEARNER REMARKABLE ORGANISATION ABILITY TO WORK BOTH AS A TEAM PLAYER AND INDEPENDENTLY

EDUCATION

Though few, I let my extensive work exerience speak for itself.

Intro to Programming Completing January 2024

Grade II Pharmacy Guild 2010

Cert III in Business Administraion MEGT Institute 2007 - 2009

CAREER HISTORY

ROWIE THE LABEL

MARKETING MANAGER FEBRUARY 2022 - CURRENT

Starting with ROWIE The Label as a freelancer during my time running eHolistics, I was eventually offered a full-time role due to the wisdom, proven methods and customised strategy I brought to the table.

As soon as I began my full-time position, I was able to work closer with the Brand Manager to drive more impactful activations through the strategy I had built for them. Without an eCommerce Manager, I happily took on the role of Marketing Manager as well as supervising the eCommerce team to lead the business development and success.

By doing this, I was able to provide the team with valuable skills for a better understanding of SEO & copywriting, to visual merchandising & conversion rates, and I've been proud of what I've been able to deliver in both the marketing strategy and building up the small team we had there. To this end, I developed and executed the brand strategy across each department by implementing new procedures alongside new documents to use, creating an easy, clear workflow for each team member for better communication, briefing and productivity. Briefing a Digital Marketer each week, I was able to build new reports for better strategic thinking, to create funnels across each channel and retain customers through their journey, no matter if they're a new customer, old customer, wholesale customer or global customer.

Again, I'm proud to have been a key team member in driving digital and online growth by building up not just the strategy, not just the brand, but the team as well.

EHOLISTICS

OWNER & OPERATOR SEPTEMBER 2020 - JUNE 2022

Due to heavy demand, I began a venture on my own, assisting local companies in a range of different industries. From Health & Wellness and Medicinal Marijuana to Fashion and Coffee Shops, I was able to grow my skill set rapidly to be more inclusive.

My specialty was providing a service completely different to that of a Digital Marketing Agency, as again and again I would watch these agencies take these clients for a ride with unsustainable methods, spending unnecessary budgets and only reap the reward for themselves with incresible commissions.

As I had the experience to merge both the creative marketing world with the technology world, my strategies revolved around driving holistic growth by marrying Paid Advertising, Social Media, EDMs and the Website Technology.

AFENDS

VISUAL MERCHANDISER APRIL 2017 - APRIL 2018

ECOMMERCE MANAGER APRIL 2018 - AUGUST 2020

Starting as the Visual Merchandiser in April 2017, I quickly grew my career in the company by proving to be a valuable player with my unrivalled experience and vast knowledge of the online retail world and understanding of systems and structures. In my early days in the company, I created new systems and procedures to aid in the post-production management of photoshoots, as well as assisting in the graphic design of emails. I would also copywrite for these emails, where I then picked up the job of building, planning and scheduling the weekly email program. As a disciplined visual merchandiser, I applied science to visual tactics of my daily merchandising to draw and intrigue my customer's eye and wrote basic coding for application functions and web development. I began assisting the Marketing Manager in building PPC campaigns within Facebook Business Manager and built weekly and monthly reports in Google Analytics and Excel to provide the company an overview of PPC performance and weekly, monthly and yearly growth. With the Marketing Manager's departure, I took on the digital marketing and worked closely with the Marketing Director to drive the paid advertising. Quickly, I obtained the buying role for the online store for my previous experience and appreciated awareness of trends. It wasn't long before I began hiring and managing a rapidly growing team as the Ecommerce Manager. Directing a small team of eCommerce Assistants and Visual Merchandisers, and supervising the Marketing and the Customer Service departments. Here I developed and executed the digital marketing strategy to propel growth and began assisting in range reviews prior to buying to ensure the company was moving in the right direction for the desired outcome. Through rapid growth, I eventually began to manage and brief external agencies to run our digital marketing and my internal team continued to grow as I took on a more focused role in digital strategy, buying, sales planning and management of the team.

I was proud to drive unprecedented growth and launch a number of global stores and strategies, including Afends USA and Afends EU.

PRINCESS POLLY E-BOUTIQUE

VISUAL MERCHANDISER + BUYING ASSISTANT APRIL 2015 - APRIL 2016

WAREHOUSE STOCK MANAGER DECEMBER 2011 - APRIL 2015

Beginning my journey at Princess Polly in the warehouse, I started by supervising the incoming stock area and organising weekly photoshoots of new garments, ensuring each individual product was counted accurately and punctually, added to the back-end systems of the online website, described and ready to make live. This involved working within a social media team as well as my own amazing team and interacting with the stylist, photographer and photo editor to guarantee a smooth flow of the procedures I have devised.

Quality control and inventory management was a big part of this job and required communicating heavily with all suppliers and brand managers. Each week I produced daily reports on stock received and shoot prep, and a weekly report on the shoot productivity.

After displaying a talent for analytics, trend spotting and startegic thinking, I was promoted to the position of Fashion & Buying Assistant, a right hand position to the CEO created specifically for me.

right hand position to the CEO created specifically for me.

Part of my duties here included providing a budget for buying, alongside analysing product data for repeat opportunities, and reviewing product inventory to maintain stock levels. I was constantly sleuthing the website both on the front-end and back, visually merchandising

every category on the website based on best sellers, new stock and repeats, and adding items to sale that no longer perform.

I created best seller & shoot reports weekly, entered invoices through Quickbooks daily, where I also tracked budgets & spending and sent out a daily report on the matter and assisted the buying team on trends & forecasting, new stock and new brands outreach.

I would assist customer service with stock queries, and occasionally work as an office all-rounder and fill in stylist.

In the more creative aspect I ran the Facebook full-time for a period, and part-time as we grew and hired a Social Media Manager. I contributed creative social media content & videos to both the Instagram and Facebook, providing stock advice for content and also working with the creative team closely to organise creative shoots and campaigns, where I would also make sure content and products were uploaded in synchronicity. Each week I would help create content for social use by the way of flat-lays and social/outfit/lifestyle images.

Through Adobe Bridge & Photoshop, I helped edit images and I also created the upload schedule each week based on the best styles, weekly newsletters, creative shoots and campaigns. It was my job to make sure the team involved with editing and uploading, and also the Social Media Manager, kept to this schedule tightly and efficiently. I was heavily involved in all the uploading, creating styles through related

products, reviewing every image, product and description before activating on the website, and ultimately running a back-end terminal to make the products live on the website.

During my time here, and continuing in to my next position, a colleague and I began a relationship with the Animal Welfare League of Queensland where we made regular donations, hosted fundraisers and helped find homeless animals new homes. AWLQ is a company I hold dear to my heart as it continues to inspire and teach other companies about animal rehabilitation over euthanasia.

UNITED DISCOUNT CHEMIST

GRADE 11 PHARMACY ASSISTANT SEPTEMBER 2008 - DECEMBER 2011

My main duties included delivering a high standard of customer service by providing product knowledge, giving advice and making recommendations, while always treating my customers and my co-workers with respect and kindness. I worked heavily in assisting the Point of Sale with ticketing and signage, stocktaking, stock control, seeing Product Representatives, entering and receiving invoices, merchandising, placing merchandise and stationary orders and setting up displays for catalogue. Other duties included general housekeeping, assisting with prescription procedures, depositing banking, operation of front shop equipment, opening and closing procedures, operating an NDSS sub-agency and stock replenishment.

PT & SONS ELECTRICAL

BUSINESS ADMINISTRATOR SEPTEMBER 2007 - FEBRUARY 2009

While completing a Certificate III in Business Administration, I worked here where my duties were to place orders to organise and prepare all of the accounting (income and expenditure), invoicing, quoting and pay rolls, for which I created and set up systems to enable fast and neat paperwork, I also corresponded with clients and wholesalers through email, travel and telephone, as well as general administration duties.